Rebekah Lawrence

4130 Old William Penn Hwy, Murrysville, PA 15668 412-651-0114

rebekah.lawrence@rocketmail.com

"I have always found Rebekah to be a friendly, outgoing and well liked person, who has a real sense of honesty and loyalty. She has a strong work ethic, she is conscientious and always aims to succeed."

Saul Jenkins

Former School Director

"Rebekah was always organized and we admired how patiently she listened to the children explain concerns or issues. Rebekah is very responsible and thorough making sure each child felt special in

William Kent

class."

Parent of Former Student

Professional Profile

I am a passionate teacher with the desire to bring students an exciting and encouraging environment to learn. I choose to be a positive role model for my students allowing them to succeed in their education.

- Earned Elementary Educator's K-6 certificate in Pennsylvania.
- Certification for English as a Second Language (ESL) K-12 in Pennsylvania.
- Obtain 2 years of experience as a classroom teacher in an International School and tutoring in a Spanish speaking country.

Education, Honors, and Certifications

B.S. in Elementary Education with an Endorsement in ESL Toccoa Falls College, Toccoa, GA

Provisional Certifications

PA State Elementary Education. 2013

PA Program Specialist Certification in ESL (K-12). 2014

GA State Early Childhood Education. 2010

Leader of Language Arts committee for NEAS and CIS accreditation at Punta Cana International School.

Teacher of the Month in October 2010

Other Certifications

CPR, First Aid, and Fire Safety training.

Key Qualifications

Certified in Elementary (K-6) and ESL (K-12)

Advanced in speaking Spanish.

Plan classroom instructions by writing weekly lesson plans. Designing yearly scope and sequences while assisting in curriculum development and standards.

Organize parent and teacher conferences, forms of assessment, and quarterly grades.

Integrate diversity and cultural awareness in the classroom as well as implementing classroom instruction for specific needs and/or skills.

Knowledge of various technologies used in teaching such as smart boards, Jupiter Grades, Work Sampling, and educational software programs/websites.

Rebekah Lawrence

4130 Old William Penn Hwy, Murrysville, PA 15668 412-651-0114 rebekah.lawrence@rocketmail.com

"Ms. Lawrence likes to be part
of all the school activities, she is
competitive and proactive making
her class outstand at all times."

Jossette Cuello
Former Elementary Coordinator

puts a lot of effort and perseverance...She is also a team player and has very strong work and service ethics."

Armando Reid

President of Macao Surf Camp

"...Becky is very patient, she

Other Experiences and Qualifications

- Worked in building a curriculum for Social Studies and Language Arts while under the process of NEAS and CIS Accreditation at Punta Cana International School.
- Developed High School and Elementary "Reading Buddy" program.
- Organized a book donation of over 500 books to assist in building the School's Library and its resources.
- Assisted the school librarian in correlating a book catalog, creating monthly themes, and informing teachers in a workshop "How to Integrate the Library in your Classroom".
- Worked as an English tutor at the Learning Shine Center, where I tutored ESL students from various countries and languages (e.g. Polish, Dominican, etc.).
- English tutor for the Surfer English Exchange, where I developed lessons to teach native Dominicans English in exchange for surf lessons.
- After school English tutor for under privileged students enrolled in the scholarship program at Punta Cana International School.
- Led an extra-curricular "Movie Club", where students enhanced their English skills through English children films followed by interactive comprehensive activities.

Employment

- Administrative Assistant, June 2013 to present TND of Pittsburgh, Monroeville, PA
- HeadStart Lead Preschool Teacher, November 2013 to June 2013
 East Suburban YMCA, Plum Boro, PA
- 2nd Grade Classroom Teacher, August 2010 to June 2012
 Punta Cana International School, Punta Cana, Dominican Republic
- Learning Shine Center Tutor, January 2011 to January 2012
 Punta Cana Village, Punta Cana, Dominican Republic
- Student Teacher, January to April 2010
 Liberty Elementary School, Toccoa, GA
- America Reads Reading Tutor
 Stephens County School District, Toccoa, GA

References available upon request.